SEGUN SANGOSANYA

< Fullstack Developer />

| $oldsymbol{\triangle}$ | sangosanyasegun@gmail.co |
|------------------------|-----------------------------|
| 0 | https://github.com/flamezba |
| 9 | Lagos, Nigeria |

aba/

A Full-Stack developer with over five years of real-world experience building web applications that match client needs. I am confident with the skills and talent that I had earned with my past working experience across different

I have developed several web applications from scratch, at the same time, I used to work on clients existing projects as I have outstanding debugging skills.

I love my work, and that helps me deliver in a much professional way.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer - AstraTech NG (part time)

Aug 2017 - Present

Location: Nigeria

- Building and maintaining the company's website and an array of product offerings.
- Plan, organize boot camp programs for the company.
- · Led development team to build web projects with tools and frameworks ranging from backend to frontend using node.js, mongodb, react.js, vue.js, PHP, Laravel
- I contributed to the development of in house tools used to evaluate creative people's skills and log them.
- Developing, coordinating, maintaining code base.
- · Lead Facilitator of their training services.
- · Contribute to the improvement of documentation standards, tools, and processes.
- · Modernized our management app originally built on HTML & Jqeury to React.js

Fullstack Developer - Powdera Healthcare Products Limited (contract)

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

Location: Abuja, Nigeria

- · Created Documentation for their ERP Solution.
- Training of 20+ staffs about their ERP Platform
- Installation of the ERP Solution on a Local Area Network(LAN) to be used in the factories and head office.
- · Led Data Migration from their old platform to the new ERP platform using MySQL and MySQL Workbench

Fullstack Developer - Accelerar (contract)

August 2018 - Nov 2018

Location: Port Harcourt, Nigeria

- · Developed and maintained an ERP solution (for Health Sector) using Laravel PHP and MySQL
- Translated ui/ux designs to reusable frontend codes using Vue.js
- Assisted in building 100% reusable code and libraries for future use
- · Worked with PM to keep track of project timeline and billing
- · Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Collaborate closely with Product, Site Merchandising, Design, and fellow engineers to develop and iterate on the responsive site experience

Developer - Nigerian Women In Information Technology (NiWIIT) (contract)

August 2017 - Nov 2020

Location: Ibadan, Nigeria

- Designed official website using Wordpress
- · Managed the website for maintenance and upgrades

Developer - DJ Mightee (remote contract)

May 2017 - August 2017

Location: London, UK

- Designed a music blog using Wordpress
- Created a music player plugin for the wordpress template
- · Created a service reservation plugin for the wordpress template.

Fullstack Developer - SammyTech (fulltime)

Jan 2016 - Feb 2017

Location: Ibadan, Nigeria

- Customized and built Wordpress Templates Using HTML, CSS, JS, PHP
- · Identified and implemented dynamic web solutions in accordance to company standards and best practices
- · Started Learning Laravel PHP, used it to build some school projects
- · Rewrote HTML to meet industry and company standards for SEO and Accessibility
- Maintained Code in the team using version control system BitBucket

Developer Intern - Experial Tech (Internship)

Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

Location: Lagos, Nigeria

- Assisted the development team in building 10+ wordpress sites using plugins like woocommerce, Wbuilder
- Worked closely with the team to re-write legacy HTML4 code to HTML5, focused on responsiveness and web accessibility. Used CSS dynamic preprocessor LESS for styling.
- With Swagger i created a new documentation of a REST API developed for a Bulk SMS Project
- Tools/Technologies JavaScript, Git, HTML/CSS/LESS, PHP, CodeIgniter, Wordpress, Bitbucket

SKILLS

Frontend

HTML, CSS/SASS/LESS, Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Styled Components, Framer Motions

State Management

Redux, Redux Toolkits, Vuex, Pinia

Backend

Node.js, Express.js, PHP, Laravel

Testing Frameworks

Jest, Mocha, Cypress, StoryBook, PHPUnit

Productivity

Slack, Trello, Jira, Notion and more

DataBase

MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, GraphQL, Prisma

Other Skills

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

Great Leadership

EDUCATION

The PolyTechnic Ibadan

Diploma. Computer Science 2014 - 2019

LEADERSHIP

President Computer Science Department

The PolyTechnic Ibadan 2018 - 2019

Nigeria Computer Society (NCS)

Member Since 2018

Lead-Facilitator CodeX Program

AstraTech NG 2016 - Present

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Yoruba (Native)

INTERESTS

Music

Video Games